

#### **CONTACT**

+44 (0) 7393 637 307

timanand@gmail.com

29 Jersey Road, Osterley, London TW3 4BQ

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ arvinder-anand-6913071ab

https://github.com/timanand

### **SKILLS**

- IT Consultation and Strategy
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Exceptional Customer Service
- Software Requirements Analysis
- Optimization and Maintenance
- Defect Management & Troubleshooting
- Agile Methodologies Expertise
- Software Design and Programming
- Software Troubleshooting
- Business System Analysis
- User Interface/User Experience
- Team Supervision & Mentoring
- Operational Support

#### **EDUCATION**

- BSc (Hons) Computer
  Science (Class 2; Division 1)
  University of Westminster
  (London)
- BTEC National in Computing (7 Distinctions and 3 Merits)
   Acton College, London

# Mr. ARVINDER SINGH ANAND (ARVI)

Nationality: British | Availability: Immediate | Driving License : Full UK

# • PROFILE SUMMARY

Over the last 2 years, I have indulged in working as a Web Developer (C#, ASP.Net Core, Entity Framework, SQL Server) working on application tickets. Prior to that, I have many years working on Windows Desktop applications (Winforms) C# and VB.NET. Throughout my career, I have worked in teams as well as on solo projects covering all the stages of the software development life cycle. My next step is to up-skill in web technologies. I have recently been upskilling myself in ASP.NET Core V7.

I'm currently studying the edX Front End BootCamp course in the evenings which covers HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and WebAPI.

I have excellent communication skills and open to working as a Web Developer, Winforms Developer, SQL Developer, Product Owner, Scrum Master, or Applications/Software Trainer.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Understanding Stakeholder requirements / writing them as User Stories with Story Points and Prioritise User Stories.
- Ability to interpret specifications for operational and performance requirements for software systems.
- Experience in building software systems that have been successfully delivered to customers.
- Expertise in requirement analysis, coding and testing various modules in a software development life cycle.
- Implement new solutions as well as add additional functionality to the underlying code base.
- Generate a clean, maintainable, and testable code, following the best practices in the industry.
- Detail knowledge of agile methodology.
- Logical, efficient and detail-oriented with critical thinking and problem-solving skills to resolve issues.

# **P** TECHNICAL SKILLS

Skills	Design Patterns
C# (.NETCore 5, 7 / Web API / Entity Framework)	Singleton Design (Creational)
C# (WinForms) .Net Framework 4.8	Factory Design (Creational)
VB.NET (WinForms) .Net Framework 4.8	Observer Design (Behavioural)
SQL Server 2014, 2016, 2017, 2019 and 2022	Unit of Work (Behavioural)
Unit Testing : NUnit, XUnit and MSTest	Repository (Domain Driven Design)
TeamCity (Continuous Integration)	Generic Repository (Domain Driven)
Octopus (Continuous Deployment)	MVC Architecture
GIT (Source Control)	
Managing Agile projects – all stages of life cycle	

## PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

**.NET Developer –** ICBC Standard Bank

July 2022 - June 2023

**Technologies Used:** C#, ASP.NET MVC, MS SQL Server, BMC Control-M, TeamCity, Octopus, Git/Git Extensions, Jira, and Confluence, Sailpoint and Cherwell.

**Duties:** Bug Fixing on Risk/Regulatory systems, Liaising with Users, RTB / On Call Support

#### Accomplishments

- Fixed critical bugs and data issues on different systems within timescales
- Looked after data feeds of different systems
- Automated manual tasks saving time and money
- Learnt the processes and workflows quickly

#### **ADDITIONAL INFO**

#### Sport

- > Table-Tennis
- Badminton
- Tennis
- Pool
- Walking

#### Other

- > SLR Photography
- Dining
- Cinema
- Travel
- Reading
- Yoga
- Volunteering

#### **Senior Associate Developer - Kainos**

**Aug 2021 - April 2022** 

*Upskilled in Technologies:* ASP.NET Core MVC, Web API, SOLID, Async/Await, xUnit for Unit Testing and System Integration Testing, Visual Studio Code, GitHub Desktop, TortoiseGit. Background reading on Javascript, Vue.js 3, Xamarin, Azure Functions.

Duties: Bug fixing in ASP.NET MVC, writing support documentation and upskilling in newer technologies like ASP.NET Core and Web API.

# **Associate Consultant –** Affinity Systems (made redundant) **Apr 2016 – June 2021** British Airways Pensions client site

Project Management, AGILE, C#, VB.Net, .Net Framework, WinForms, SQL Server

**Technologies Used:** .Net WinForms (C#, VB.Net), OOP, SOLID, LINQ, SQL Server (Relational Database Design, SQL Queries. Stored Procedures, Functions, Views and optimising SQL Server Queries and Stored Procedures), TDD: NUnit, Agile (Scrum), Visual Studio, MS Teams, Crystal Reports, HTML, VBA.

- Responsible for using best practices and delivering successful products.
- Met strict project deadlines by working well independently and also within a team setting.
- Mentored and inspired Junior Developers to gain confidence and develop quality software.
- Effectively translated client requirements into successful applications (all stages of dev. life cycle).
- Provided outstanding technical support to clients / liaising with third party suppliers within targets.

#### **Accomplishments**

- Devised the Management Authorisation System that totally eliminated any paper processes.
- Developed the automation of monthly critical processes saving several man days per month.
- Engineered the business-critical Governance System which allowed smooth running of operations, visibility of breaches, and improved staff productivity by 30%.
- Inspired a Dashboard system that constantly checks for any errors in the various systems. This resulted in 25% improvement in solving issues at first hand.
- Pioneered various tools that allowed individuals to work from home i.e., structured discussion message system, 'Who's Here?', 'What's Happening?', 'Who's Doing What?' and 'Who's Where?'.
- Developed a User Skills Matrix system providing employee skills scoring for management staff.

#### C#, VB.Net Developer - SafetyKleen

Apr 2015 - Feb 2016

Market Leading Industrial Surface Treatment

Technologies Used: C#, VB.NET, SQL Server, Agile, MS Test, Kanban, and Git Source Control.

- Maintained, supported, and developed existing business critical systems.
- Responsible for the operational day to day running of the key C# / VB.Net applications.
- Performed analysis, design and development of the application according to the user requirements
- Designed and piloted prototype applications. Learnt benefits of Pair Develop. and Testing
- Liaised with Business Analysts and developers a provided Business applications support.

#### Senior Analyst/Programmer - InPractice Systems Sep 1993 - Feb 2015

**Technologies Used:** C#, VB.Net WinForms, Agile, Sprint Plans and Daily Scrum, Ranorex Automation C# Libraries, DevExpress for WinForms, Visual Studio, PostgreSQL, Perforce for Source Control, Seapine Test Track Pro for bug defects, Tortoise SVN, HTML and XML.VB6, Access, FoxPro, Oletools, ImgX Tools, ImagN', Farpoint Spread and Infragistics Ultrasuite.

- Responsible for designing, developing, maintaining apps in C#/VB.Net WinForms, VB 6
- Designed and developed reporting applications using Crystal Reports.
- Wrote solid efficient, maintainable and reusable code in Software House.
- Automated testing in C# using Ranorex libraries and followed Agile Sprint Development.
- Developed design skills, handled pressures of accreditation testing and then applying immediate fixes.